<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on DataFibers</title>
    <link>https://datafibers-community.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on DataFibers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2020, DataFibers all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 13:50:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://datafibers-community.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Naive Bayes Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://datafibers-community.github.io/blog/2018/03/10/2018-03-10-ml-naive-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datafibers-community.github.io/blog/2018/03/10/2018-03-10-ml-naive-bayes/</guid>
      <description>Background It would be difficult and practically impossible to classify a web page, a document, an email or any other lengthy text notes manually. This is where Naïve Bayes Classifier machine learning algorithm comes to the rescue. A classifier is a function that allocates a population’s element value from one of the available categories. For instance, Spam Filtering is a popular application of Naïve Bayes algorithm. Spam filter here, is a classifier that assigns a label Spam or Not Spam to all the emails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Overview</title>
      <link>https://datafibers-community.github.io/blog/2018/03/02/2018-03-02-ml-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datafibers-community.github.io/blog/2018/03/02/2018-03-02-ml-overview/</guid>
      <description>Background Machine learning is a field of computer science that gives computer systems the ability to &amp;ldquo;learn&amp;rdquo; with data, without being explicitly programmed. Machine learning can be broken down into three broad categories: Recommender, Classification, Clustering.
 Recommender—Recommender systems suggest items based on past behavior or interest. These items can be other users in a social network, or products and services in retail websites. There are some algorithm like Pearson correlation and euclidean distance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>